无上的主啊,请与我同行
Almighty God, in my hour of need, be with me
我永远不会忘记那神圣的誓言
Let me never forget my sacred and holy vows onto Thee
我在这个苦难的世界里斩妖除魔
and I should not be prey onto demons and devils, and all the dark things of this world
用正义武装我的身躯
Honour me with the armor of Thy righteousness
赐予我宝剑,助我发现敌人
Give me the sword of truth, that I shall confound mine enemies...
直至成为真正的骑士
... and be onto Thee... the true knight
攻进皇宫去
They blockade the path!
这边
This way!
当心
Guard!
后撤
Fall back!
快撤
COVEEER!!
- 雅各布,我们可以阻止  - 现在阻止会损失更多人
- Jacob, we can stop this.   - Stop now, we lose more men.
这场血战在所难免
There is no stopping this
- 我们要包抄他们  - 里边有妇女和儿童呢
- We can outflank them.   - There are women and children in it.
- 不会伤害他们的  - 肯定会
- They won't be hurt.   - They WILL be hurt.
今天必须结束战斗
We end this today!
跟我来
WITH ME!!
陛下
Your Highness.
- 求助就可以取胜  - 来不及了
- With Allah's help we may still prevail.   - The time for false hope is over.
我对你只有最后一个请求
There is one final request I must beg of you, my friend.
你还没打够吗?帮那些伪善的神父作战
Haven't you had enough of this-killing for hypocrite priests?
- 那是上帝的意志  - 我们这是在滥杀无辜
- We do God's work.   - The blood we spill here is on our blades.
是我们的灵魂在堕落,不是上帝的
Our souls, not God's!
我们再也不用这么做了,可以走了
We don't have to do this anymore. We can just go.
- 去哪儿?  - 东方
- Go where?   - East.
去你的东方吧
No one goes East.
- 那里没这里惨  - 你质疑我们的事业吗?
- Cannot be any worse than here.   - You doubt our cause?
- 你不是发号施令的人  - 没一个是
- You're not the man you once were.   - None of us are.
那就去你的东方吧
Go there. Go East!
要知道,我对你父亲发誓过
You know, I swore an oath to your father.
我父亲死了,你走你的
My father is dead, you are released of your oath.
我走我的,滚
I release you. Go!
- 父王  - 爸爸
- Father.   - Papa!
阿欣会护送你走
Hassan will escort you away from here.
趁现在还能走,快点
I will see you again... very soon.
你必须坚强
You have to be strong.
为了孩子们,为了我们
You have to be strong. For the children, for us.
亲爱的
My love.
冲啊
GOD WITH US!!!
我们决斗吧
Stop, this is finished.
走
Leave.
(绝 命 逃 亡)
(远东地区 三年后)
我大限将至,儿子
My days draw to an end, my son.
- 不,父王  - 是的,昭
- No, father!   - They do... child.
这是自然规律
That is the nature of life.
现在仅剩的
All that is left for me...
就是确保我的国家找到一个明主
...is to ensure my Kingdom receives the leader it deserves.
所以我选择了你
Which is why I have chosen you...
取代我
...to sucseed me.
- 我?可是星...  - 你皇兄是个大将军
- Me? But... Shing?   - Your brother is a great warrior.
现在是和平时代
Now it's the time for peace
这是我对你的要求
That is my request of you.
父王,没人会追随我的
NFather, no one will follow me.
会的
They will...
因为你会是皇帝
...because you will be King.
陛下,星王爷到大门外了
Majesty, Prince Shing approaches the gates.
时间所剩无几了
Our time is less than we thought.
元龙,拿玉玺来
Qiang Long, the royal seal.
遵命,陛下
Yes, your Majesty.
元龙会护送你
Qiang Long will escort you...
一定要让昭平安找到高将军
...ensure that you all safely reaches the General Sen Ching Wen.
我会誓死保护他的
I will protect him with my life.
我是不会轻易决定的
I have made none of these decisions lightly.
所以我选择了你
Which is why... I have chosen you.
父王
Father.
莲,你虽然不能继承皇位
Out of necessity, Lian.
但父王对爱女的爱...
A King... tends more to his sons.
并不亚于对皇太子的爱
But it does not mean... he has any less love for his daughter.
我把你弟弟的性命交付于你了
I trust you... with your brother's life.
他是江山之后
With the future of our Kingdom.
走
Go
快走
Go now.
陛下
Majesty.
- 久违了  - 确实久违了
- It's been a long time.   - Too long, my son.
我一接到您龙体欠安的消息就赶来了
I came as soon as I heard of your declining health.
你一直惦记着朕的龙体啊
My health has always been a concern of yours.
我一直都关心你,父王
I have other concerns, father.
但坊间传闻甚多
About... rumors I've heard.
传闻?你杀了那么多妇女和儿童
Rumors... are the distraction of children and old women.
是的,确实不假
Indeed. Unless they are true.
还有什么传闻?太可惜了,儿子
And... what rumor carries... such weight, my son?
我已经传皇弟前来商讨大事
Perhaps we should summon my baby brother to discuss it?
抱歉,你的皇弟已经出宫
Unfortunately, your brother is away from the palace.
看来你的决定太草率了
I fear your ill health is clouding your judgement, father.
皇位是属于我的!
The throne is my BIRTHRIGHT!!
是你欠我的
I earned it, fighting your wars!
没有你,就没有这个国家
Without you... there would be no Kingdom...
我的一切
... but everything!
我为你牺牲一切
I've given everything for you.
我知道,儿子
I know... my son.
但请你高抬贵手
But please...
这是子民的福祉所在
...it is in the best interests of the people.
- 什么?你了解子民吗?  - 星皇子
- What... do you know about THE PEOPLE?!   - Prince Shing!
吾儿并无恶意
My son means me... no harm.
父王对你信任有加
My father must trust you very much.
你有家人,有妻儿老小
You have family? A wife? Children?
我一定会把你的孩子赶尽杀绝
Resist me and I will see that your children are nailed to the walls of your home...
- 一刀一刀的  - 星
-...one piece at a time.   - Shing!
你妻子要被我的卫兵蹂躏一辈子
That your wife spends the rest of her life pleasuring my guards.
为王捐躯的日子一去不复返了
Die for a King whose time has passed...
快选择服侍新主吧
or choose to serve a new one.
下去吧,出去,全部退下
Leave us. Out! All of you.
记得这把匕首吗,父王?
Remember this blade, Father?
你母后曾经用它来救我的命
Your mother... once saved my life with it.
在我小时候,她送给了我
When I was old enough... she gave it to me.
还说我会登基
And told me I would be King.
但你不是她的宠儿
But you are not the child she loved.
玉玺在哪儿?
Where is the seal?
Where. Is. The. Seal?
老天不会原谅你的
Heaven... forgive him.
老天接近你了,都是你咎由自取
Heaven is closed to me... because of all the things I've done for you.
陛下驾崩了
The King... is dead.
是被我的皇弟昭所杀
Murdered. By Prince Qiang.
他夺走玉玺,给我找到他
He stole the royal seal. Bring it to me.
跟我来
Follow me.
控制好你的手下
Keep your men under control.
传高将军进宫
Summon General Gao.
好了
Now.
,我该如何发配你的家人?
Or should I send for your family?
快点
The horse!
杀了他们
Stop them!
走
Go!
我们继续走吧
Maybe we should just keep going?
走不了多远的,没马了,我们需要求助
And how far will we get? We have no horse. We need help.
- 你留下  - 莲,应该是我去
- You stay here.   - But Lian, I should go!
父王选择你,因为他知道你很坚强
Father chose you, because he knows you are strong.
不管怎样,你都要继续走,你会找到将军的
Whatever happens, you keep going. You reach the Generals.
做你的皇帝
And you will be King.
千万当心
Be careful.
来
Here.
没钱就别想吃
No money, no food.
当初你进来的时候,我还以为你是白幽灵呢
When you first came in, I thought you might be the White Ghost.
看来我错了
I guess I was wrong.
那是公主吗?
Is that the Princess?
我想找护卫
I seek an escort for the road.
我有钱
I can pay.
死人要钱干什么?黑衣护卫在猎杀你们
What use is coin to the dead? The Black Guards are hunting you.
看我看到谁在外边转悠了
Look who I found skulking outside!
昭
zhao
对不起,我没发现他们
I'm sorry, I did not see them.
- 我父王会知道的  - 他早死了
- My father will hear of this.   - So the dead have ears.
不,我父王没死,不是真的
No, my father is not dead. It's not true!
哦,是吗,还是你杀死他的
Oh, you know it is. After all it was you who murdered him.
- 或者是你,莲公主?  - 是星
- Or was it you, Princess?   - Shing.
玉玺在哪儿?
The seal, where is it?
可以吧?
You mind?
抓住他们
Hold them.
不,住手
No! Stop it.
还给我!
Give it back to me!
- 玉玺是我的!  - 杀了他们
- The seal is mine!   - Cut these throats.
不
No
NO
剑是我的
The sword... is mine.
它属于我
It belongs to me.
我想要回来
I'd like it back.
过来拿啊
Then come.
拿着
Take it.
鸦片
Opium.
你这种傻瓜,收拾他
Your kind are such fools. Clean him up.
宰了他
Kill him.
- 莲  - 昭
- Lian.   - Qiang!
对了,这孩子死定了
Either way, the boy dies.
- 杀吧,我只想要回剑  - 给你的话,你就走?
- Kill him then, I just want my sword back.   - If I give it to you, then will you leave?
你一定要帮帮我们
You have to help us.
祝你好运,公主
Good luck, Princess.
且慢,请留步
Wait!
当心点
Much obliged.
等下,昭,来
Wait. Qiang, come.
求你了,帮我们吧,我们必须去行云城
Please!Help us. We must get to Shing Yuing.
你会得到荣华富贵的,我们有黄金
If your reward is what you seek, we have gold.
我弟弟是江山最后的希望了
My brother is the Kingdom's only hope.
你不帮我们,我们会被杀的
If you don't help us, we will be killed.
走,留在这只有死路一条
Come. You will be if you stay here.
驾!
Jia
想动手就动吧,有人来了
Do what you must, but there are riders down below.
- 多少人?  - 叫醒他,轻点
- How many?   - Wake the boy. Quietly.
- 嘘,我们必须藏起来  - 什么?
- Shh. We have to hide.   - What.
继续搜
Keep looking!
驾!
Jia
你怎么回来了?
Why did you come back?
你拿回你的剑了
You had your sword.
是你说有黄金的
You promised gold.
反正我也要去那里
And I was having that way, anyway.
你去那里做什么?
What brings you to our lands?
我知道,但我们只有这些了
I know. But it's all we have.
停下
Let's stop.
等着我
Wait here.
我叫你等着
I said, wait.
这都是我们的错
This is our fault.
- 他们需要求助  - 我们需要离开,走
- They need help.   - We need to go, come on.
你不能一走了之
You can't just go!
等下
Wait!
这怎么可能?
How is that possible?
- 放开我  - 快走
- Let me go!   - Come on!
不客气
You're welcome.
没事了
It's great.
我们是来帮你的
I'm only trying to help.
好吗?
All right?
- 我叫莲  - 我叫昭
- I'm Lian.   - I'm Qiang.
你呢?
And you?
小丽
Xaoi.
好名字啊
Beautiflu name.
不能丢下她
We can't just abandon her.
又多一张嘴吃饭,又要多藏一个人
It's one more mouth to feed, and one more body to hide.
是三个,不是四个
They seek three, not four.
好吧
All right.
那一箭,你是怎么做到的?
That shot. How did you make it?
练习
Practice.
我们进山回到林子里
We go off the map, get through the woods.
但愿一路上不会再遇到黑衣护卫
Hopefully we won't see any Black Guards until Ching Shao.
陛下,高将军到
Your Majesty, General Gao.
- 星王爷  - 是陛下
- Lord Shing.   - Majesty.
你手下有多少将士奉命保护他?
How many of your fellow generals will offer support to the boy?
一旦诏书下发,就要举行仪式,没有仪式了
Once the Council has officiated over the appropriate ceremony...
得先有玉玺
... can't be no ceremonies without the seal.
但是,既然玉玺在他手上,那就没办法了
But... if he... has the seal, there's nothing to be done.
他谋杀父王
He murdered my father.
抢走玉玺
Stole the Seal.
如果这样
If that's the case...
他会受到相应的惩罚
...he will be punished. Accordingly.
罪不可赦
It's inexcusable.
皇太子也不例外
Even from a Prince.
请见谅,将军
Forgive me, General.
父王被杀,令我心灰意冷
My father's murder has left me overemotional.
他们会去行云城
They will be heading to Shing Yuing.
一定不能让他们得逞
Make sure they never get there.
对不起,星的手下滥杀无辜
I'm sorry, for what Shing's men did.
他也杀了我父亲
He murdered my father, too.
为什么?你们没收了我们的犁头
For what, a few coins and a rusty plough?
那不是我们的错
Does it matter what it was for?
我会改革的,帮助你这样的百姓
I want to make things better, for people like you!
你以为我这种百姓能改善生活?你高高在上的
Do you think it makes a difference for people like me-who sits on the throne?
应该能,我会改善民生的
It should. And we change things.
你不信我?
You don't believe me?
我不信你,你还那么小,而行云城还远在天边呢
I believe you're just a boy, and Shing Yuing is still faaar away.
但比昨天更近了
And yet, it's closer than yesterday.
在这里宿营
We'll make camp here.
喂!
Hei
可恶
Shit
我需要它
I needed that.
那是摧毁人意志的力量
Tear of the poppy. Dull the man's senses.
总比清醒要好
Some things are better dulled.
我们的性命和国家的命运
Our lives and the future of our Kingdom...
都仰仗你了
... depending upon your wits.
那是你的国家
Your Kingdom.
你背井离乡
You're far from home.
是在逃亡吗?还是在搜索?
Are you running? Or searching?
两者都是
Both.
你们的人
Your people...
- 相信有地狱吗?  - 我们相信你
-... do they believe in Hell?   - We believe in Diyu.
周围都是死神
The realm of the Dead.
社稷江山都在等我们振兴
One is assigned to one of 18 levels.
不能出错,不能再有血雨腥风
A place of heart. The Lake of blood.
有罪就必须要惩处
The punishment fits the crime.
你有什么罪?
What was yours?
我作恶多端
Ohh... there've been many.
我们都有罪要赎
We all have our weights to bear.
公主肯定不用...承担重负
No doubt, the life of a Princess... is a heavy burden.
你知道在这个世界做女人是什么滋味吗?
Do you know what it's like-being a woman in this world?
你以为眼睁睁看着生灵涂炭,就没有负担吗?
Do you think watching men destroy everything you care about bears no weight?
因为什么?荣耀?
And for what? Pride?
贪婪?
Greed?
你们士兵一定要创造新世界
You warriors march off and forge new worlds.
我们一定要保护孩子
We have to stay behind, to raise the children.
我们一定要为父王报仇
We have to explain why their fathers don't return.
我们还一定要惩罚那个畜生
And we have to fix the broken creatures that do.
不要批评我的生活
Do not judge my life.
- 你根本就不了解女人  - 对不起
- When you know nothing about being a woman.   - I'm sorry.
公主也是人
A Princess... is a woman, too.
我以前什么事都依你
I am, what you wanted of me.
我做了你下不了手的事
I did what you needed, but couldn't.
我会如愿以偿的
I will have what is mine.
醒醒
Wake up.
我想像你那样射箭
I want to fire arrows like you.
教教我吧
Teach me.
求你了
please
教我
Teach me!
我还以为白幽灵不用洗澡呢
I thought White Devils didn't bathe.
这是远离家乡养成的恶习
A man picks up bad habits when he is away from home.
你征战无数,我也想成为一名勇士
You've been in many battles? I wish to become a great warrior, too.
可父王让我读书,不让我习武
My father wanted me to learn from books, not have to fight.
教我吧
Teach me!
- 为什么?  - 为我父王
- Why?   - My father...
星必须付出代价
Shing must pay.
求你了
Please.
教我吧
Teach me.
战争需要技能
Battle is both craft and art.
首先你要勤学苦练
First you must learn to craft.
然后取得进步,直到行动和反应成为本能
Then you push past it, until action and reaction become instinct. A part of you.
教你的人武功高强吗?
The man who taught you, was he a great warrior?
腰一定要挺直,肩膀放平
Use your back, allright? Not your shoulders.
放
Release.
射箭
Fire.
放
Fire!
对不起
I'm sorry!
没关系
Better.
你对我弟弟真好
You're good with my brother.
这孩子心地善良,头脑聪明
The boy has a good heart and mind.
跟他姐姐一样
Like his sister.
一直往东走的话,早就到行云城了
If we'd gone East, we'd already been nearing Shing Yuing.
你以为黑衣护卫不知道吗?
Where do you think the most of Black Guard are concentrated?
所以我们要绕道而行
Once we get past Ching Shao, there is less chance that they follow.
我弟弟走到哪儿,他们就杀到哪儿
They follow where my brother instructs.
白色骑士也杀过你的人
In the Silver Mountains there said to be bandits who despise your brother and his men.
你指白幽灵?
You mean the White Ghost.
难道你不一视同仁吗?
Wouldn't he despise us equally?
安静,蹲下
Quiet, stay low.
我们要快点走,上马
We should move on, quickly, Mount off.
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
青纱城
Ching Shao.
所有人都在找你们
Everyone will be looking for you.
得设法进城
We need to find a way in.
- 你好  - 你好
- Greetings.   - Greetings.
我在带我家小姐和她的男仆赶路,想找个伴
I'm travelling with my mistress and her servant boy, searching for new company.
这个要求一定可以满足,只要价钱合适
You will find us extremely hospitable, for the right price.
你和你家小姐可以跟着我们
You and your lady are welcome to join us.
她很害羞,喜欢一个人
She's shy, she enjoys her privacy.
到了城里,那就更喜欢了,那里可全都是陌生人
She will enjoy it so much more in a city full of strangers.
你把你的黄金给他了
You gave her your gold.
我想等我们到达鑫源会付你钱的
I'll see you are properly rewarded when we reach Shing Yuing.
不要说话
Stay calm.
让开
make move
这必须慢点来
Dismount slowly.
- 下车  - 有什么问题吗?
- Out of the cart!   - What seems to be the problem?
我们在找殿下和公主
We are searching for the Prince and Princess.
你在里面是找不到让你有兴趣的东西的
You'll find nothing of interest here.
让他们通过
Let them through!
快,我们走
Come on, let's go.
你做得很好
You did well.
你们应该跟我们在一起
You should stay with us.
我想我的女主人更愿意自己上路
I think my mistress would prefer to keep travelling.
你们都累坏了,想想孩子吧
You're exhausted, and think of the children.
我有特权,你们也同样会有
I have private rooms, your mistress will appreciate the privacy.
你看什么啊
Waht are you looking at?
你们要比看起来更饿
You are hungrier than you appeared.
带我的客人去沐浴,他们一定累了
Take my guests to clean up. They must be tired.
留下
Stay.
我可能有你感兴趣的东西
I have something that may interest you.
一定要确保自己的旅途安全
Make sure you are fit to travel.
谢谢你的好客
Thank you for your hospitality.
这是为你身体着想
It's all to your health.
这边走
This way.
- 你没事吧?  - 我当然没事
- Are you all right?   - Of course I am.
- 他也为我们服务  - 有人说他不是吗?
- He served us well.   - Did anyone say he hasn't?
现在快去夕照
Now go and get cleaned up.
明天第一件事就是离开这里
I want to be ready to leave first thing tomorrow.
- 太早了  - 照我说的做,昭
- It's still early.   - Just do as I say, Xiaoli.
失陪一下,我有生意要照看
If you'll excuse me, I have some business to attend to.
你给我喝的是什么?
What did you give me?
抓住他
Help the man!
很显然他不胜酒力
Apparently he can't handle his drink.
你们要的不是他,我会给你数不清的钱
It's not you they want! They're worth more money than you've ever seen! Your share alone!
我已经有了
I already have a mistress.
- 快走  - 发生什么事了?
- Come on, you have to go. Come on, now!   - What happened?
我们走,我们落入陷阱了
Let's go! We've been betrayed.
- 快点  - 等等,我们的马呢?
- Hurry, this way.   - Wait, our horses!
骑马是无法通过关卡的,到河里,找船
You'll never pass the city gates. Go to the river and find a boat.
下了船,在山上等我
Head downstream, wait for me at the Silver Mountain.
- 那里是荒山  - 我知道,所以我才要去
- There are bandits!   - I know, that's where I was going.
- 你呢?  - 我会去找你们的
- And you?   - I'll meet you there.
如果我没来,就在山上
If I don't arrive, Shing Yuing is a day beyond the mountain.
我还不知道你的名字
I don't even know your name.
快走,快啊
Please Lian, go. Go now!
好了,快走,走啊
Allright, just go.
都解开
Untie them all.
快搜查房子
Go search the building!
别杀他
Don't kill him yet!
他们在哪,快说
Where are they? Speak quickly.
告诉我,否则我杀了你
Tell me now, or I kill you.
将军,发现殿下和公主划船往山上去了
General, Prince Qiang and Princess Lian are on the river headed toward the Silver M ountains.
找到他们
Go after them.
快到河边去
Get to the shore!
快跑
Run!
放开我,放开我!
Let me go! Let go!
张嘴
Open your mouth.
不要...
Don't don't...
好痛
hurts
很好,
good
要是我的话就让你烂掉
It was my choice, I would have let you rot.
天哪
God
- 你怎么在这?  - 够了
- My companions?   - Safe!
就因为你们,官兵铺天盖地
The Black Guards are as thick as flies on a fart ask because of you.
是你们把他们引来的
You brought them here.
你是怎么找到我的,拉德
How did you find me, lad?
没有人会去东边
Nobody goes East.
你知道吗
Remember?
几乎没人活着回巴格达
There is few of our kind beyond Baghdad.
- 我们需要谈谈  - 我们没话好说了  - 拜托
- We need to talk.   - We have nothing to say.   - Please.
我应该就把你留在树林里自生自灭
I should have left you in the woods.
他没有...
But you didn't.
等你能走就快离开
As soon as you can move, you leave.
加蓝,拜托
Gallain. Gallain, please!
- 他走了?  - 暂时的
- Please. He lives?   - For now.
你就是他们称为白幽灵的坏蛋?
You're the outlaw they call the White Ghost?
我就是白幽灵
I am the White Ghost.
但是没人叫我坏蛋,孩子
But no one calls me outlaw, child.
在我的面前没有
Not to my face!
你的朋友带我们来的
Your friend sent us here.
我的朋友?
My friend?
你们想着他能依靠?
And you expect that to count in your favor?
- 你救了我们  - 我也可以杀了你们
- You saved our lives.   - Well, killing Black Guards, that was no hardship.
你们活着还有用
Your lives have value.
是的,我亲爱的
Yes, my love.
- 把他们送回去领赏  - 我会杀了你的,坏蛋
- Shing will pay handsomely for your return.   - Or he might just kill you. Outlaw!
如果我们能够逃脱我哥哥的追杀,我就是国王
If we escape my brother, I will be the King.
- 你多大?10岁?  - 14岁
- How old are you? 10?   - 14!
- 我为什么要帮你?  - 我会给你报酬的
- And I should help you, because?   - I will give you a reward!
- 只要我们能够自由下山  - 现在,我不知道
- And you may come down from this mountain! A free man.   - Now, I do not know.
我的经验告诉我
In my experience those who climb to...
国王是不会赦免坏人的
...the top only ever remember they got there by their own effort.
我会忘记的
I won't forget!
也许你会,也许不会,还需要时间才知道
Maybe you will, maybe you won't. I need time to think.
很幸运,我的老婆喜欢你,我的酒在哪?
You are lucky my wife likes you. Where is my wine?!
放了他们,他们想跑就跑
Free them, they got nowhere to run.
你们曾经是朋友?
You were his friend.
我们曾经一起作战
We fought alongside one another.
- 他以为你死了  - 他是对的
- He belives he's damned.   - He's right.
我们所有人都是杀手
We were, all of us-killers.
但是他
But he became...
更进一步
...more than that.
你们都是做这个的
That what warriors do!
有的人被血吞没了
Some get a taste for blood.
他不是其中之一
He is not one of them.
曾经我想要这一切都是真的,就像你现在做的一样
There was a time I wanted that to be true, as much as you do now.
至少他还能够看到其他人的希望
At least he still sees hope in others.
会拿起剑为他人,而不是去做自己的游戏
Puts his sword at the service of that, rather than his own game.
陛下,有消息
Your Majesty, we have news!
备马
Saddle the horses.
雅各布
Jacob...
我叫雅各布
My name is Jacob.
很高兴认识你,雅各布
Nice to meet you, Jacob.
- 对不起  - 为什么?
- I am sorry.   - For what?
如果没有你,我们是到不了这里的
We'd never have come this far without you.
你也基本可以做到
You... don't have to do that.
我知道,我想要你
I know. I want to.
除了看着昭吃东西,你什么都没做
There's not much else to do here, except watch Xaoi eat.
他因为你才活下来的
She lives because of you.
我们都是
As do we.
也许你是在为你杀的人赎罪
Maybe you've repaid your debt.
休息吧
Rest, for now.
别走,请你抱着我
Please, help me.
我一定得见见他
I must see him.
干嘛
What?
女人,你够啦啊
Oh man, don't you ever stop?
妈的
Here, fucking opium.
你是鬼魂吗?
It keeps the ghosts away, huh?
这是我的魔法
This is MY medicine.
她那天看到了
What you saw that day...
是什么让你来到这里,你走了老远却是徒劳
If it's forgiveness that brought you here, you've come a long way for nothing.
不用你来告诉我这是个错误
Perhaps you've come to tell me it was some terrible mistake?
你没杀他们
That you didn't kill them? Huh?
我不能告诉你
I can't tell you that.
但是我保证,他们不是死在我的剑下
But they did not die by my sword, I promise.
这事情让我很头痛
Riddles give me headaches.
孩子
The children
被他们的母亲杀死
were killed by their own mothers.
女人被冤死
The women died by their own hands.
因为你会成为什么
Because they fear of what you have become.
是
Yes.
那是什么?
What is it?
我以为你说过上帝会原谅你
You think if you save this boy, God will forgive you?
可是上帝不存在
Men can not know God's will,
他们想要去的时候,
and when they pretend to...
用血来结束
... it ends in blood.
我们喝的就是血
That I'll drink to.
你怎么了?白幽灵不在了?
So what happened to you? The White Ghost, bandits?
我已经试过了
I tried my hand as a merchant.
让黑色的守卫挡住了我
But the Black Guards took all I had.
我的妻子
My wife
她的刀法不错哦
she's good with a knife, aint't it?
但是有一次,见到了最美的
But in one time... she had the most... beautiful...
景色
singing voice.
上帝
But the... Guards...
却把她的舌头割掉了
... cut out her tongue!!
让我的右眼瞎了
Blinded my right eye.
但是我还能听到
But I still have her.
但是你的剑依然是个问题
Which is all that really matters.
如果是星成了国王
If Shing becomes King,
这个地方会成为焦土
this land will burn.
所有的地方都会成为焦土,雅各布
All lands burn, Jacob. You know that.
你比任何人都清楚这一点
Better than anyone.
我得去尿尿
I have to take a piss.
你应该休息的
You should be resting.
我比你更年轻更健康
I'm younger and healthier than you.
我跟我的父亲保证过
I made a promise to my father.
我发过誓
I swore to him...
我会用生命保护昭
... I'd protect Qiang with my life.
但是你
But you...
是为什么呢?
...why?
我一直用错误的方法去寻找上帝
I once looked for God in all of the wrong places.
但是你,你的弟弟
But you... your brother...
让这一切变得说得通
It started to make sense again.
我的弟弟会赦免你的
My father would have liked you.
我不知道
Ohhh, I don't know.
我想你的父亲会杀我的头
I think your father would have taken my head.
用真的剑
And rightly so.
还记得第一次见你
Perhaps to the man we first met.
但是你
But you...
你是我爱的人
he would have loved.
是吗,我...
Lian, I...
他已经出去几小时了
He's been out there for hours.
有正确的人辅佐他,会带来和平
With the right people by his side he will hold the peace.
你听起来被那个公主迷住了
You sound like one of those priests
你必须为她拔剑
that blessed us as we marched off to war.
说到幽灵
The ghosts...
- 你真的见过?  - 只是上帝见过
-...you really see them, too?   - Only when I let my guard down.
他们会怎么问你?
And what do they ask of you?
- 他们说了是吗?  - 他们不需要说
- Mine don't talk.   - They don't need to.
如果他们说了呢?
And if they did?
死亡低语会是什么?
What would the dead whisper?
一定要血债血偿
What is ought, must be paid.
这不是我们来决定的
It's not for us to decide when, though.
你为我们所有人做的
To the damned, each and every one of us.
现在要努力做到
You are not hard enough on him.
- 葛雷恩,有了你的帮助  - 不
- Gallain, with your help...   - No!
我跟你说过了
I told you before!
我不会再为他人战斗了
I'm done fighting other men's causes.
你可以将他们交给星
Ah, you could have handed him over to Shing
我是个平民
I'm a simple man.
很容易就会被年轻的公主说服
Easily bedazzled by swift-talking young Princess.
你什么都是
You are many things,
就是不简单
none of them simple.
他们已经到达河堤了
They have... reached the riverbank.
我们别无选择了
We have no choice now.
全力准备吧
Make what preparations you can!
没有人能够活下来
No more that four bombs in each bag.
我选这个地方是有原因的
I chose this place for a reason.
我们会尽量在山下杀掉他们的人
We beat them down below, take as many as we can.
- 并尽量迷惑他们  - 然后撤退掩护
- Bring confusion.   - Fall back to the caves?
昭,你留下
No, you stay here.
但是这都是为了我
But they're here for me.
如果你死在山上,你就无法做你的皇帝了
And if you die on the Mountain, you will never be the leader your father wanted.
保重
Be careful.
举起盾牌,盾牌,防御
SHIELDS!! SHIELDS UP!! SHIELDS!!!
快射箭,放箭
Return fire! RETURN FIRE NOW!!!
后退
Fall back!!
快回到洞穴
Get back to the cave, now!!
回到洞穴,在那里消灭他们
Back to the cave, we'll finish them there!
快走
LET'S GO!!
回去洞里
Get your sister and Xiaoli back to the inner cave.
我应该留下
I should stay!
你无需证明了
You've got nothing more to prove,
好吗,如果我是你的话就藏好
all right? Men have died for you, don't let that be in vain.
快走,快
Go! Go now!
就是现在
Mei!! NOW!!
御林军
The Black Guards!!
快走
GO!! GO, MEI, GO!!
走
Go...
带上孩子,快走
get the boy... now!
想要我的血吗?
You want my blood? You want my BLOOD?!
你没事?
The others?
加蓝挡住他们,我们必须马上离开
Oh, it's just Gallain. We have to leave, before more Black Guards arrive.
我能看见你们
I see you...
这是谁?
...woman...
还有你
I see you...
昭,莲
Qiang Lian
白色猴子
and the white monkey.
你是帮他们的?
Did you help them?
还是跟这个人一伙的?
Or was it this one?
不,我想这是白色幽灵才对
No. I think this one is the White Ghost.
为什么?
Why?
因为
Because...
这孩子喜欢我们
...the boy isn't like us.
我们喜欢什么?
And what are we like?
没有我们,世界将会是一片战争
The world will be better without us.
你呢?
And you...
小兄弟
little brother.
你真的觉得你能够登上王位
Do you really think bandits and barbarians can win you the throne?
我们的父亲将会讨厌你现在的样子
Our father would hate what you have become.
看来我应该先杀了你
Then it's probably a good thing you killed him.
你今天流了很多血
You've spilled a lot of blood today.
让我们看看还剩多少吧
Let's see how much you have left.
不!
NO
放倒他
his bow, dies!
小心点,莲
Careful, qing
别杀了自己
You might cut yourself.
别再这样了,星
No more, Shing...
不要
no more...
莲,不要
Lian, no!!
星陛下已经死了
Lord Shing is dead.
莲
lian
- 姐姐  - 你会没事的
- Sister!   - I'll be all right.
你在想什么?
What were you thinking?
在我的国家
Of my country...
昭
zhao And Qiang...
我爱你
I love you...
对不起
I'm sorry.
陛下
Your Majesty.
请原谅我
Please, forgive me.